



Jairo Gätjens







San jose, Costa Rica

email: jgatjens@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I have worked as a software engineer for more than 15 years leading teams, working on hiring processes, personal management, creating architectures in different areas, projects with tight deadlines and new technologies. Some of the biggest companies and brands I have worked for includes: elancohub.com, interwellhealth.com, ni.com, OrTracker App, mergeworld.com, wunderground.com, 18techs, criticalmass.com, www.cafebritt.cr, hangarworldwide.com, www.pcfinancial.ca, Clorox - Britta +, Jerry García, among others.



SKILLS

- Experience in Typescript and Nodejs.
- Headless development (XMCloud, Contenful, Strapi 3/4, GraphQL, Rest).
- Extensive experience creating design system with Storybook.
- Javascript (React, Angular 1/2, Backbone, Gulp, Webpack, Rollup, Vite).
- React Native, Ionic.
- Redux, Jotai, React Query, SWR vercel.
- Ajax, Observables, Promises.
- Tailwind CSS, Chakra UI, Radix, Shadon, (Sass | CSS Modules | Style Components).
- Nextjs, server components, i18n, Next auth.
- Vercel pro and Enterprise account management.
- 10 years ago C#, C++ and PASCAL.
- Postgres, SQL, MySQL and Microsoft Access databases.
- Backend: Nodejs, prisma or drizzle.
- Mac, Ubuntu, Windows environments no problem.
- SEO optimizations and implementation with AA2.
- Graphic and UX design background.

- Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch, Photoshop.
- · Learning Japanese and Threejs.

WORK HISTORY

<u>lu-studio.dev</u> – Owner

Mar 2022

- We offer global, practical and effective solutions for businesses that (seek, want) to create high
- quality user
- friendly experiences. We engineer next level user interfaces tailor made for any clients needs.

18techs.com - Full Stack Developer

Set 2021

- Working with an amazing group of people.
- Responsible for creating demos and full products for clients.
- Create Figma prototypes.
- Create style guides and design systems for backend integration.
- React, Next.js, Storybook, Nodejs, etc..
- I enjoy sports (soccer, surfing, and skate surfing).
- PC and macOS environments.

<u>hangarworldwide.com</u> – Technology Lead

Jan 2020 - 2021

- Career developer
- · Work on ni.com projects
- Create unit tests for ni.com projects
- Custom storybook components (angular and vanilla javascript)
- Create a small design system for hangarworldwide.com
- Create programs for people level skills
- · Talk directly with clients
- Responsible for creating demos for clients
- Follow Agile methodologies (Azure)
- Create Figma prototypes
- Help with ni.com design system

<u>18techs.com</u> – Full Stack Developer

Apr 2016 - 2019

- Work on OrTracker React native app, Web App, and Node API.
- Work for mergeworld.com.
- Create multiple static and dynamic WordPress sites.

- Create style guides for multiple sites.
- Create SPA using react and angular.
- Migrate www.wunderground.com to angular
- Work with multiple APIs
- Server side rendering with Expressis
- Unit test with jasmine
- Use of Agile methodology (Jira)
- D3 and D3 server side rendering
- Foundation

<u>hangarworldwide.com</u> – Front End Lead

Jan 2009 - Mar 2016

- Generated a methodology for Code Reviews at least once a month within the Front–end department.
- Fostered an environment to lunch and learn at least once a month
- Acted as a leader in terms of technology. Manage deliverables, raise flags (risks), and ensure that the projects cames on time and in compliance with the estimate.
- Scheduled and conducted one on one at least every 15 days with all my team members.
- Created tasks for people who were available.
- Collaborated with the Technology Directors, Project Managers, Creative Leads, and Account leads to design, develop and deliver digital marketing projects on mobile, web, and desktop platforms.
- Functioned as a leader and coordinator of the Application Developers,
 Web Developers, and Database Developers.
- Ensured successful involvement of Project Management, Quality Assurance, and Release Engineering team members.
- Assisted on the architecture and development of multiple projects.

Organizational Consulting Group S.A.

- Programmer (visual 6.0 and C#)

Oct 2008 - Jan 2009

<u>coopecorl.com</u> – IT Guy

Mar 2008 - Oct 2008

- Designed Web
- based (Java/JSP) Internet applications linked to Oracle databases.
- Analyzed business, functional, and technical requirements.
- Technical Support.
- IT tasks like windows updates, windows problems, new installations, users' specific requests, etc...

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

<u>Universidad Fidelitas, Costa Rica</u>

- Bachelor's in Computer Science

2005 - 2008

<u>Universidad Latina, Costa Rica</u>

— Electrical and Electronics Engineering

2011 - 2012







